get the Honorable Nathan guy she I think
it's appropriate to acknowledge this
bill has good cross-party support and
had its first reading in December 2009
that received 57 submissions and 31 of
those were heard by the finance and
expenditure committee and the committee
work particularly well through this
process and made some useful refinements
to the bill the bill generally focuses
on licensing and prudential regulation
for all insurers carrying on insurance
business in New Zealand all insurers are
to be licensed and supervised by the
Reserve Bank they must comply with
Prudential requirements the Reserve Bank
will be both the regulator and the
supervisor it aligns New Zealand with
international regulatory benchmarks and
expectations it is a standalone rather
than an adjunct of the Reserve Bank Act
its primary purpose arms to chair as the
promotion of a sound and efficient
insurance sector and the provoke and
overall the promotion of public
confidence in the sector which I'm sure
the house would agree is particularly
important the bill overall will cover
all the categories of insurers carrying
on carrying out business in New Zealand
life non-life and indeed medical all
insurers must have a financial strength
rating except the very small insurers
and the friendly societies will insurers
must have a satisfactory fit and proper
and risk management program and life
insurers must maintain a statutory fund
to protect their long-term policy
liabilities as I mentioned before mr.
chair the Reserve Bank
we'll have broad information gathering
powers as supervision including an
active role in the management of
distressed insurer's the bill has
extensive stakeholder consultation and
its purpose is an approach that
generally been accepted by the industry
are all shane jones motor